# María Alejandra Pérez

# UX / UI Designer

UX / UI Designer with a passion for user-centric solutions and workflow optimization.

By efficiently researching and communicating with stakeholders and customers I design useful, honest, and accessible processes and products that understand the customer's struggles and motivations as well as the business needs.

# **Contact information**

- mapb1989@gmail.com
- **.** +34677709274
- Barcelona, Spain
- in @mapb1989
- mariaalejandraperez.com

#### **Skills**

#### **Technologies & Tools:**

Figma | Sketch | Adobe XD | Invision | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin | Miro | Notion | Maze

#### Soft skills

Problem solving |
Adaptability | Time
management | Empathy |
Listening

#### **Hard skills**

Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design

# Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Proficient

German: Beginner

Catalan: Beginner

## Work Experience

10/2020 – present **UX/UI Designer (Freelance project)** 

FixFirst (Berlin, Germany) [Remote]

SaaS provider for service partners and technicians of home appliances

Design SaaS solution and app for Startup POC

- Collect requirements and feedback from clients to improve user flow and information architecture of application and desktop dashboard.
- Build components library for UI Designs.
- Create Mockups and prototype of new mobile application targeted to
- technicians.
- Redesign and prototype existing SaaS desktop solution for service partners and contact center.
- Redesign and prototype technicians website.
- Run demos and usability tests to find points of improvement in the designed products (iterative work).

05/2018 – 04/2020 Lead Customer Support and operations Engineer

Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

Software provider of Smart WiFi and proximity marketing

- Manage support team.
- Analyze, improve and maintain the company's operational processes.
- Report, replicate and track bugs in the production environment.
- Provide training and support to customers as required.
- Manage customers' projects from contract signature to end of installation.

### Projects

05-06/2020 App for streaming services recommendations

UX/UI Final Project at Ironhack (UX Research, IA, Interaction design, UI Design.)

Goal: Offer accurate recommendations for movies and shows streaming services.

Other projects can be found at mariaalejandraperez.com

#### Education

12/2019 – 06/2020 **UX/UI Designer** 

Ironhack (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2014 - 02/2017 Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona, Spain)

09/2007 – 12/2012 **Electronic Engineer** 

Universidad Simón Bolívar (Caracas, Venezuela)